my story tonight is government
surveillance and
I realize most people would rather have
a conversation about literally
any all the topic including is my small
on giving me cancer to which the answer
is probably
all do goldfish suffer from depression
to which the answer is
yes but very briefly but the fact it's
it is vital but we have a discussion
about this now because an important date
is just around the corner one big data
service circle on the calendar when it
comes to a very controversial subject
the reauthorization of the Patriot Act
and
all of the controversial provisions
there in June 1st they've gotta come to
an agreement to reauthorize
or curtailed his program yes some
controversial provisions within the
Patriot Act
a pager tact all set to expire on June
the first so circle that tight
on your calendars everyone and while
you're at it circle June 2nd as well
because thats Justin Long's birthday you
all forgot last year any
he noticed cow over the last couple
years
you probably heard a lot about strange
sounding programs such as
X ke school muscular prism and mystic
which %ah coincidently also the nines
have some %uh florida's least popular
strip clubs
welcome to XK school all told his a
fully on rejected and shoes by his
warning lights
but but if you don't mind I would like
to refresh you memory over some things
and let's stop by focusing on the most
controversial portion of the Patriot Act
that is up from renewal section 215
which on the way
sounds like the name all Eastern
European boy backed
we all section 215 prepared to have your
hearts
slobodan in her says the
at the camp along with the bad boy water
struggle but I saw Obama and the one
without annoying deficiency their
incredible
but the contents all the real section
actually even more sinister top section
215 nicknamed
the library records provision which
allows the government to require
businesses to hand over records have any
quote any
tangible things including books records
papers documents
and other items that sounds brought it's
because
it was pretty much written that white
section 215 said the government can ask
for
any tangible things so long so long as
its for an investigation to protect
against international terrorism which is
basically a blank check
assaulting a teenager borrow the car on
the street condition
but I only use it for car related
activities
okay mama dot I'm going to use this for
a hand job
in the Wendy's parking lot but that is
car lighting so I think I'm public's
section 215 is overseen by a secret
intelligence course known as the fully
support
and they've interpreted it to mean the
government could basically collect
install phone records for every American
the vast majority of whom of course
have no connection to terrorism unless
on cheryl has been greatly miss
characterizing activities a needlepoint
Klopp
it's a sleeper cell evening on Cheryl he
will happen for this on Shoal
you're trying to I'm a terrible alt not
in that order
now the government will point out that
on the 215 by hold
phone records and not the calls
themselves
what the
intelligence community is doing is
looking at phone numbers
and rations have calls they are not
looking at
people's names and they're not looking
at content yes
but that's not entirely reassuring you
can extrapolate
a lot from that information 8 if I can
you you called your X
12 times last night between one and 4i
at for a duration a fifteen minutes each
time
I can be fairly sure that you left some
pretty pathetic for smiles
Don't Tell law during this call Vicki we
should play together
pick up the phone to cuba got a ball
no the Patriot Act was written just
after the 9/11
and for years it was extended and
reauthorized with barely a possum
thought
in fact became sole routine the winnings
extended in 2011
one newscast just tacked on to the end
report about a presidential trip abroad
chip Reid CBS News traveling with the
president in Deauville France
also in France by the way President
Obama signed into law a four-year
extension of the terrorism playing
Patriot Act
also in france boy at the white
hogging the limelight he threw that in
like a mother telling her grown daughter
than a childhood pet just died
ok much talking to you sweetie also by
the way mister purpose is dead see you
at Christmas by
put all attacks was before the public
was made aware of what the government's
capabilities
actually were is that all ended in June
Edwards noted it's just taking
responsibility for one of the biggest
government leaks
in US history we learn that the
government has the capacity track
virtually every American phone call
and a scoop up impossibly bass
quantities of data across the internet
revelations that the NSA eavesdropped on
world leaders
if you've ever been to the Bahamas the
NSA could have recorded your phone calls
and store them for up to a month
yet all that information was exposed by
Edward snowden
and it is still kinda incredible the
29-year-old contract that was able to
steal top secret documents
from an organization literally has the
word security
in its nine clearly that was not great
for them
because the only place where should be
that easy for employees may 22 steel
israel needs store told the short shirts
like this
relax dude it's a Miami Marlins cap
we're not exactly selling Faberge eggs
here
in it is still unclear
exactly how many documents and what's
not install
although he is consistently tried to
reassure people that he put them in good
hands
honestly I'm dole wont to be the person
making decisions on what should be
public watchin
which is why rather than publishing
these on my own
are more putting openly I'm running
through journalists
and that sounds great but of course it's
not a final site plan
as was proven when the New York Times
published this law and
but it's such a sloppy job locking out
with ducted information that some people
able to reach the information behind
that black ball
which concerned how the US was
monitoring al Qaeda emotional
a group now known as I sis so
essentially
a national security threat was leaked
because no one in the times knows how
teams
Microsoft Paint and look
you can think that's not only did the
wrong thing
all did it in the wrong way but the fact
is we have this information now
and we no longer get the luxury pleading
ignorance it's like you call go to
SeaWorld
a pretend the shallows happy anymore
when we now know
at least of the water in her tank is
while tears
we know that now you called all know
that information
so you have to bear that in mind but
here's the thing:
it's now two years later and it seems
like we've kind of gotten to have a tick
bite
over the content what's known linked
recent Pew report found that nearly Hall
Americans site and not very concerned or
not at all concerned
about government surveillance which is
fine if that's an informed opinion but
I'm not sure all
that it is because we actually sent a
camera crew to time square
to ask some random passersby who Edward
snowden walls
and what he did and these are the
responses that we got I have no idea who
averaged known as
and now I have no idea where we're
snowed in this I've heard the name
I just can't picture think right now
exactly what it is
Edward snowed in no I do not
just for the record that wasn't
cherry-picking that was entirely
reflective everyone we spoke to
although to be fair some people didn't
remember his nine
I just couldn't remember why he sold
some information to people
here be open information
that
shouldn't have been revealed think from
what I remember is the information that
he shared was detrimental to our
military secrets
and keeping our soldiers in our country
safe begin leaked documents
but the US army's operations in Iraq
average no
revealed Ubuntu secret I guess ur
information in the wiki
WikiLeaks worse now than we he's inside
a weekly
edwards known revealed a lot of
documents to Wikileak ok so here's the
thing
and what's known is not the wiki leaks
got WikiLeaks guy
is Julian assaults I'm you do not want
to be confused with him
partly because he was falling
scaffolding snowden in what he released
and how and partly because he was it was
a sandwich bag for the biscuit tall
wearing a speedy next week
the I'm got his got his practical
Suva songs is not a likable man even
Benedict Cumberbatch
could not make him likable he's own
comeback schiphol
call was supposed to be physically
impossible
but I don't blame people for being
confused
we've been looking at the story for the
last two weeks i think is hard to get
your head around
not just because there are so many
complicated programs to keep track of
but also because
there are no easy answers here week all
naturally
want perfect privacy and perfect safety
but those two things
cannot coexist it's like how you can't
have
a bad aspect Falcon and an adorable pet
vol.9 herbert's
a
a do you have to lose one of them which
obviously you don't want to do
we have to accept some reasonable
restrictions on both of them
now to be fair the NS I will argue that
just because I can do something
doesn't mean they do to it and that they
all restrictions
on the operations such as the political
which must
approve requests phone surveillance pops
in 34 years
that course is approved over 35,000
applications
and only rejected 12th yes much like
Robert Durst second wife
the phones the court is all longingly
except
in Miserables a look at a los Q too many
questions I'm just gonna give you the
benefit of the doubt that you clearly
don't deserve
at least tell him to blink and book less
those the public might be the most
troubling thing about that shop so
so maybe it is time for us to talk
about where the limits should be and the
best place to start
would be section 215 not just because
it's the easiest to understand
because there is widespread agreement it
needs to be reformed
from the president to Ted Cruz to both
the ACLU
and the and alrighty to even the guy who
wrote the thing in the first place
I was the principal author the Patriot
Act I can say that without
qualification congress never did
in 10 do allowable collections when it
passed section 250
and no fair reading up to text would
allow for this program
think about that he was the author
that's the legislative equivalent
Lewis Carroll saying the teacups ride at
Disneyland in sight
this has to be writing day in no fair
reading a book text would allow for this
right
you touch my publicly night I love
psychedelic pedofilia
it what a race for Victoria this is not
what I want it
and even the n/a site
has said that the number of terror plots
in the US that the section 215 telephone
records programs is disrupted
is Wong and it's worth noting that one
particular plot
involved a cab driver in San Diego who
gave eighty five hundred dollars
to a terror group and that is the
shittiest terrorist plot on ever seen
all that and the plot have a good day to
die hard
but he here's the big problem here if we
let section 215 get when you can its
current form
without series public to bite we're in
trouble because section 215 is the
canary in the coalmine
if we cannot fix that we're not gonna
fix any of them
and the public to fight two bites of all
has been absolutely pathetic
a year ago a former congresswoman was
discussing the 215 program on the news
watch what happened this vast collection
of data
is a not that useful and infringes
substantially on personal privacy i
think at this point we should
seriously consider II not shiite not
concomitant
teenage an issue comes amid let me
interrupt you just for a moment we've
got some breaking news
at Miami standby coming out right now in
Miami justin Bieber has been arrested
charges pecans drina charges
including resisting arrest and driving
under the influence is appearing now
before the judge for his bond hearing
that's what
the
all all actually you know or 5 news
we're gonna have to interrupt your
interruption all the big news for a new
interruption
this time featuring a YouTube video of a
tortoise having sex with a plastic clog
let's watch
the the
that's is essentially the current song
on this vitally important to but
her
and again all not saying this isn't easy
conversation
but we have to have it I know this is
confusing
unfortunately the most obvious person to
talk to about these
is Edward snowed in but he currently
lives in Russia meeting
if you wanted to asking about any these
issues you have to fly all the way back
to do it
and it is not a pleasant flight and the
reason I know thats
is the last week I went to Russia
to speak to ed wood snowed in and this
is what hap the yes last week I expect
48 paranoid Howard in moscow
arguably the last place on earth where
you can find in like joseph stalin
impersonator
arguing with them unconvincing fight
planning after experiencing russia's
famously warm hospitality want to meet
Edward snowed
who's supposed to show up in this room
at moon however at five minutes off to
the interview was scheduled to begin
I have a troubling thoughts on up
these comment cuz my argument is
why woody when you think about it got
two thousand rubles
the says he doesn't make it without
understanding how much that is
all I'm saying is
10 of light for an empty chair
I'm gonna lose my shit the it turns out
that many people have a problem because
all Russian producer
book to see the room directly
overlooking
the old KGB building
and the home the comment Federal
Security Bureau
we've just been told they know we're
here
someone in so that happened
um
too steep for if the Russian Russian KGB
is listed with the fire alarm if he's
not coming
shit
ok
sores or the way old
whole only she p
home the most famous hero I'm gonna try
to
a recent American history and I started
with a question designed to text his
loyalties
how much do you miss america you know
my country is something did
travels with me you know it's not just a
geography that's already a way too
complicated of the arteries
i misses the loss the greatest country
in the world I do miss my country I do
miss my home I do miss my family
do you mix Hot Pockets yes
I miss Hot Pockets very much
okay Tom the entire state of Florida
the let's just let us all contact com
truck tops you must write notes
I don't know what they are lucky for you
good not just drug knots
stars and strikes truck Knox to
is two bowls of Liberty in a freedom
sack
little head well at least one listed
no cuz abiam them
quandary d calf guess nightmare him
urine okay let's talk why
did you do this the NSA has the
greatest surveillance capabilities the
that we've ever seen
history now what they will argue is that
they don't
a use this for nefarious purposes
against American citizens in some ways
that's true but the real problem is that
they're using these capabilities to make
us vulnerable to them
and then saying well I had a gun pointed
at your head
I'm not gonna pull the trigger trust me
so
was the NSA you want look like because
you apply eat
for a job with the n/a site were you
clearly see an inherent value
in that shadowy organization I worked
with mass surveillance systems
against chinese hackers I saw that you
know these things do have some purpose
and you want your spice to be good at
spying
to be fair right what you don't want is
you don't want them
spying inside their own country spies
are great when they're on our side but
we can never forget that they're
incredibly powerful incredibly dangerous
and if they're off the leash taken in
the coming after us
but just because we're too at two
different things here domestic
surveillance on foreign soil
good domestic surveillance americans
give some other shit about
phone surveillance they don't give any
remote shit about well the second
question is when we talk about foreign
surveillance
are or we applying it in ways that are
beneficial
no one cares in terms that no I don't
give a shit
we spied on unicef the Children's Fund
shore
whose on lawyers negotiating
I holes unicef doing I mean that's the
question as in
the questions are these programs
valuable
are we going to be safer when were
spying on unicef
and lawyers were talking about the price
shrimp and cloak cigarettes I don't
think people say that's good I think
I'll say
I definitely don't care Americans do not
give a shit
I think you're right about phones like
what some people do care about is
whether snowden conceded the
adverse consequences up leaking so much
information at once
how many of those documents have you
actually read
I've evaluated all the documents there
in the archive
you read every single one well I do
understand
turned over pollute the difference
between understanding
what in the document and reading what's
in the documents
I'm recognize the concern rocking a good
one when handing over thousands of an SI
documents the last thing you want to do
is
read them I think it's fair
to be concerned about did this person do
enough where they careful enough
is working when you're handling material
like we know you're handling
well in my defense I'm not handling
anything anymore that's been passed to
the journalists and their
using extraordinary security measures to
make sure that this is reported in the
most responsible
bought those a journalist's with the
lower technical skill set than you
that's true but they do understand just
like you and I do
just how important is to get this right
so so the New York Times took
a slight didn't read acted properly and
in the end it was possible for people to
see
that something was being used emotional
on Al Qaeda that is a problem with other
Cup it is Cup and these things do happen
in reporting
in journalism we have to accept that
some mistakes will be made
this is and a fundamental concept I'll
Liberty
right but you have to own that you're
giving documents with information you
know
could be harmful which could get out
there
yes if people
act in bad faith knowing talk about bad
fight took a nap
incompetence we are but you will never
be
completely free from risk if you're free
the only time you can be free from risk
is when you're in prison while the risks
were significant
snowden himself has made it clear he
feels the rewards have been worth it
you said in your legs Brazil I was
motivated by believe this is the world
deserve to understand the system in
which they live
my greatest fear was that no one would
listen to my warning
never by being so glad to being so long
how did that feel I was
initially terrify this was gonna be a
three-day story a ruse
forget about it but win I saw that
everybody around the world said well
hope this is a problem
we have to do something about this it
felt like vindication
even in america even America and I think
we're seeing something amazing
which is if you had ask the American
people make
tough decisions to confront tough
issues to think about heart problems and
they'll actually surprise you
okay here's the problem I did ask
americans
and boy did it surprise me I have no
idea who averaged known as never heard
now and now I have no idea where we're
snowed in this
I've heard the name I just can't picture
think right now
exactly what it is well he's I'm
he sold some information to people group
B opener
information that
shouldn't have been revealed Edward
stone revealed a lot of documents to
Wikileak us
average no revealed Ubuntu secret I
guess earn information in the wiki
WikiLeaks worse now than we he's inside
the with Julie
I'm been charged with leaks
moral ideal I guess on the plus side he
might be able to go home cuz it seems
like no one knows who the
you all expect everybody
on informed so
did you do this to solve a problem I did
this
to give the american people a chance to
decide for themselves
the kind of government they want to hang
out that he's a conversation that I
think
the American people deserve to decide or
there's no doubt is a
critical conversation but is a
conversation we have the capacity
to have because it's so complicated we
don't
fundamentally understand it it is a
challenging conversations I mean it's
difficult for most people to even
conceptualize
the problem is the unit is massively
complex
and so much so that his visible service
providers
technicians engineers the phone number
let let them
let me stop you right there because this
is the whole problem ride
there's the whole problem I just glaze
over cuz it's like the IT guy comes into
office we go
all kept in Fair Mall
ship don't teach me anything don't want
to learn
you smell like cancer it's real
challenge to
figure out how to we communicate things
that require sorted years and years of
technical understanding and compress
that into seconds
up speech I so I'm sympathetic to the
problem
but the thing is everything you did only
matters
if we have this conversation properly so
let me help you out there
you mentioned in an interview that the
NSA was passing around naked photos of
people
yet this is something where it's its
not actually seen as a big deal
in the culture of an essay because you
see naked pictures
all the time that's terrifies people
grimly of people about backed this is
the response she gets
the government should not be able to get
dick pictures
if the government was looking at that
picture boards
penis I definitely feel it would be a
asiana
my perhaps yet that the government will
look at the room appears that would
upset me
they should never ever the US government
have a picture
have my day it might happen pat me a
picture of his penis
and the government can access it I'm I
would want that program
the be shutdown I would want the dick
pic
program team
I would also want the dick thing will be
correct if the program became
I would want to be tweaked I had wanted
to have have clear
and transparent laws that we knew about
I'm in our community just
not understand what they were being used
for why they are being kept
you think that programming I don't I
don't think that program exist at all
now now no no
if I had now is dead
the US government had a picture of my
dick I will be
very pisto well
the good news is there's no program
named the dick pic program
the bad news is there are still
collecting everybody's information
including your dick pics with you are
wrong on that last guy having sent a
dick pic
recently you need to guess I'll show you
like I did
that the jury innocent little girl
recent this is the most visible
line in the sand for people can
they see my dick some with that in mind
looking thoughtful thats
is a picture of my dick from from
genocide program explain to me its
capabilities
in regards to that photograph of my
penis
so 702 surveillance camera see my dick
yes the fis Amendments Act of 2008
which section 702 falls under are
allows the ball collection Internet
communications that are one and foreign
ball collection now we're talking about
my dick it's not you get pack rock
yep get so if you have your email
somewhere like gmail posted on server
overseas are transferred overseas or
anytime crosses outside the borders the
United States
your junk hands up in the database
so it doesn't it doesn't have to be
sending a pic to a German but no
even if you submit something with in the
United States
your holy domestic communication between
you and your wife
can go from New York to London and back
and get caught up in the database
executive order 12 trouble-free
article Monday I yes he'll 12 triple 3
is what the NSA uses when the other
authorities
are aggressive enough or they're not
catching as much as they'd like
for example has how how are they gonna
see my dick
I'm only concerned about my penis when
you send your junk
through Gmail for example yeah that
stored on Google's
servers Google moves data
from data center to data center
invisibly to you without your knowledge
your data could be moved outside the
borders at the United States
temporary when you were junk
was passed by gmail the in a sec or copy
that
prism prism is how
they put your junk out of Google with
Google's and Bachmann
all the different prism partners people
like Yahoo
Facebook Google the government deputize
is that
to be the sorta their little
surveillance
share their dictionary correct arm
upstream upstream is how they snatch
your junk
as it transits the Internet okay mystic
if you're describing your junk on the
phone yes
but to help the content about junk all
or just the generational it
they have the content as well but only
for a few countries
if you are on vacation the Bahamas yes
finally and you need to remind yourself
to hunt just not sure the
what to do with this it's a just a lot
just hold on to it insalata
responsibility yeah it is a lot
responsibility that's the whole point
should I no you should absolutely not
and it's unbelievable that you would do
that
actually you can totally believable I
to drifting not by
home all K they can probably tell
who you're sharing your junk pictures
with because they're seeing
who your texting with who you're calling
if you called a penis enlargement
central three in the morning that call
lasted 90 minutes
they would have a record of your phone
number calling
that phone number which is a penis
enlargement center they would say
don't know it's a penis enlargement
center but of course they can look it up
and would if the american people
understood this
they would be absolutely horrified
I guess I never thought about putting it
in the
the context to junk good
good take away from this P until such
time
as we've sorted all this out don't take
pictures in Vedic
just don't do it anymore and hold if if
we do that if we wait hold on were you
saying no
you should keep taking be yes you
shouldn't change your behavior
because I got agency somewhere 15
sacrifice our out because we're afraid
we don't care about us
values very much that is a pretty
inspiring on sir to the question
I what do you just send me a picture of
your dick to come up
America last night sold
there you have it america all about
should now be equipped to happen michael
devine
begin by June 1st it is imperative we
have a rational
adult conversation about whether of
safety is what living in the country
%uh barely regulated
government-sanctioned dictionary
with my work here is done that was just
time to take care of one more thing
finally congratulations on saddam for
winning the Oscar I know you can be at
the ceremony for obvious reasons so
ha haha thoughts which celebrates
ourselves to use Wow so it's really
who is often thank you well was the
alarm to on me
going back home safely well he weren't
on the list before you are now
the like um
to juggle both this alga
joke or user actually possible know it's
it's so that's real thing your
Associated now ok I
just to be clear and eyesight arc never
met this guy so
take me off your King list like do not
want to get stuck in Russia
you
%uh
home
well
play we got in touch with the n/a site
National Security Council and the white
house
and we ask them to comment on the dick
pic capabilities all key to the
program's and with some just discussed
which
into that we were some very funny emails
to write to government agencies
I they did not wish to comment on the
record and I can see why
every possible reason