you
hello welcome to today's webcast API
design 3rd edition if you haven't
checked it out already we highly
encourage you to check out the API craft
group on Google it's filled with folks
who are doing wonderful things around
API design API implementation and the
business of AP is this webcast and all
the webcasts that we've done in the past
and will do in the future are available
on YouTube at youtube.com slash Apogee
and the slides will be available on
SlideShare it's slideshare.net / effigy
I'm Brian Malloy you can find me on
Twitter as landlessness kevin's fire you
can find me on twitter at kevin's water
Donna moment talks a lot about design
and there's a particular article he uses
to talk about the differences between
simplicity and features you know we
always get pounded with hey we need more
features while we need to keep it more
simple and he has a quote here that I
really like that says the issue isn't
about simplicity is about design so as
we go through this today we're going to
try to give some pointers of how you can
take what's normally pretty complex and
add that usability to look forward at
the end developer as well so if you
think about it it's more like like
you're building a big cathedral right
which has so much complexity but to the
people walk you through there to the
users it has to be beautiful so that's
our goal on the agenda today we're going
to do a recap of previous editions of
this API design presentation we'd have
thought a little bit about epi modeling
how that can help you and your team
getting some issues around security or
some methods for for implementing
security new API talk a little bit about
message design get into some benefits of
hypermedia and talk a little bit about
modeling transactions so the design
materials that we've covered in the past
in the the first two editions of this
webcast are also available in an e-book
called Web API design like McDonald's
has served billions of burgers over
10,000 people have downloaded this
design book
and it's our intention to base the next
edition of the API design book on the on
the webcast that we're doing today as
Kevin mentioned in the past we focused
on some aspects of API design which are
we've recapped on this cheat sheet here
if you really look at the previous
editions of this of this content we
really focused on you are I design that
was the heart of the matter and we
hinted that some things around
versioning errors and some client
considerations so what we want to do
today is is go beyond these topics and
talk about things like designing your
messages especially the response
messages and then take a look at some
other things like what's happening with
with hypermedia great so how do you
start with our API so I talk a lot about
about API modeling and a lot of folks
have questions around that so before we
get too deep into what we can do with
some of these responses and then some of
these different methodologies we can
take on just want to spend a moment
talking about what API modeling really
is and in the software world with we do
modeling all the time this is really
using those same concepts except
applying it to your API so usually
advise folks to to collaborate with all
the stakeholders involved that's
marketing business analyst software
engineers key business people these are
folks in your epit most likely develop a
language that everyone understands and
use that language in building your
resources building out the parts of your
messages it's it's really key to keeping
everyone on the same page and of course
document how you do that is up to you
write a lot of folks use UML some people
have their own version of you know
modeling language that they use that's
that's fine whatever you're comfortable
with and then continue to iterate the
key point here is don't go off on your
own right is as soon as you say you know
what I'm going to solve this for the
company all by myself you'll put in
hours and hours of work only realize
that hey marketing doesn't really use
this term that way or this really isn't
the direction
want to go with our resources in our API
so deftly include that API team they're
really important part so security I know
through some of our FG webcast you're
talking about security before we're
going to touch on it again because it's
a pretty important thing the Twitter API
uses in for their streaming API anyway
they have the option of using HTTP basic
authentication which is essentially a
username and password base64 encoded
that's that's one way to go for sure
amazon decided to roll their own
authorization their own authentication
so they built on top of HTTP
authorization and they have this AWS
authorization type Google is using OAuth
specifically they're using OAuth 2 point
0 and bearer tokens our recommendation
is to go the google route use OAuth 2
HTTP basic is only so secure lots of
folks are moving away from it and
willing your own is a huge hassle you
don't have typically we don't have the
resources the security resources to
verify that our design is is perfect in
is it's rock solid Oh off has been
through the paces quite a bit and there
are even more secure options coming in
the future for access tokens all right
so when we approach message design
that's one of the key topics that we
want to cover today and we're going to
do that started out pretty simple here
first of all regardless of how you
design the messages you have to answer
what kind of format you want it to be in
it's our strong suggestion that you
support both JSON and XML there are
folks who have libraries that do great
stuff with accent mother be loved and
there are folks who can't stand XML have
great libraries that do stuff with JSON
that they love unless you have really
strong business requirements or
objectives that will limit you to XML or
JSON you ought to just support both and
if you're not sure about which one to
make the default pic JSON if you know
should be XML go ahead and make it XML
but you're not sure our suggestion is to
make your default JSON now over here is
talk about how you model in your in your
response message both a single item like
a single resource and also will
clutching of resources and we're going
to do that by taking a look at how
three big public api's do it what you
see here is a response from Twitter
Foursquare and Instagram for each of the
primary objects from those systems so
for example in Twitter you're looking at
a tweet in Foursquare you're looking at
the check-in and Instagram you're
looking at a media or an image and what
we do here is what we're looking at is
the top-level view of each of these so
you see twitter is pretty verbose at the
top level four square has included meta
notifications and response and instagram
has included meta and data now the next
side we're going to do a double click
down on both Foursquare Instagram to see
what they reveal beneath that so what
we've done is a single single click down
on Instagram so we're just seeing what's
inside there meta attribute and then the
force where we had just click twice once
we clicked on response and then that's a
check in and then we opened up check in
so what you see here is that real real
core object is represented at the heart
of each of these in the case of some
objects there are more verbose than
others it's question is what is written
for us to learn from this in terms of
how we go about designing our primary
resource and this is what we think you
ought to do include a property for meta
where you can put in meta information
about the object and then include the
actual name of the object type itself as
the primary where area where you hold
the data to contrast that I'm just gonna
go back one slide quickly here if you
contrast that foursquare put their
information under response and then
under checking so I like the fact they
use check-in but I don't like the fact
that they buried under response because
you've already separated the response
from the rest of the metadata by having
a meditech there and Instagram they just
call it data which is kind of really
annoying I think both to me and Kevin
yeah it's just kind of a throwaway word
so we like the idea having the dog there
and I think it's really clever what
Foursquare has done with notifications
because you can imagine every response
that you get back from the API there
might be some global state or global
information that's changed that you
could also you know take advantage of
kind of piggyback in that information on
the API response so i can surely clara
that they've included notifications in
in the response so that you know how
that translates is foremost app
developers who are using this
yeah they go okay both the notifications
coming back every time with every
response i can go ahead and include that
and kind of that information so i can
throw stuff you know at the top of the
screen or somewhere interesting in my
app so that's our guidance on doing the
resource kind of take the best of both
worlds from Foursquare and Instagram and
use a meta meta data area name your
primary resource and then include
notifications or other global
information if that makes sense so
that's the single that's a single
resource now how do we represent
collections of resources this is the
case we have more than one so we're
gonna take a look at this again now what
you'll see here is a Twitter Foursquare
and Instagram they all do pretty much
the same thing which is throwing the
objects into an array of multiple
objects and with one minor exception
this is an important point Twitter
Foursquare and Instagram all include the
same exact information in the collection
that they do in this single so that if
you're thinking about how you make this
decision for your API as Kevin and I
were talking about it I think both of
our inclination was well what you really
want to do is provide a limited subset
of the data in the collection and then
when you want to drill down it then you
provide the poor bigger verbose thing
with the idea that you're going to
preserve on bandwidth but I at least
meeting I know if you won't go to I
really warm up to the idea of including
the same exact information in both of
the collection and in the single in the
single response just because there's a
sense of predictability there and it
seems more deterministic and you count
on it being there the one exception that
i mentioned is actually Foursquare
includes one extra property called
source the standalone resource they
don't include on the collection I'm not
really sure what the what the point of
that one was so you can pair other stuff
together my feeling is do the same thing
make sure you include that metadata
include your notifications or other
global information that impact the app
and then you know put in the nice
portable version of the primary resource
in this case it would be dogs for our
modeling include all that same
information that was that would be
included in a single resource and you're
off and running now if you have a
ridiculous model where the single
resource is super huge and you are
worried about bandwidth then you can
kind of trim down the one that goes in
the
and although Kevin doesn't always agree
with it you can use partial selection to
help you narrow that down as well and
you can see the previous versions of
this talk professional selections so to
do search results this is an important
point this is actually a quote from the
Facebook API documentation selecting
results is not the same as searching and
sometimes it's easy to over-exaggerate
why these are separate activities but
essentially the idea of searching is you
can create a just some sort of natural
language string in the query box and it
can search across resource types so
instead of limiting to say select like
hey giving all the photos you're saying
generally give me anything about fubar
and you get the results across all the
resource types so you're let's take a
look at how three api's approach this
this is being their search api google
custom search and read it for searching
their listings and without taking a lot
of time to drill into the details of
what is coming back in the response
design here just keep in mind that there
is metadata about the results there's
another data about the query and then
there's the actual data itself that is
being we is being returned from the
search so it pretty overwhelming you'd
be would start digging into this to
figure out which stuff should you
include in the search response in which
stuff should you should not so here's
our suggestion for the most part follow
Google custom search they do really good
stuff on this well we did those we took
the key pieces of metadata that they
included we just they put it under a
different couple of nested objects we
just consolidated all under one metadata
property so here we're saying include
the limit and offset for the pagination
include the total results that are
available because that's how do you want
to do pagination in a family way and
important to include the the query
string that that was sent to make the
crew happen and then if you want to show
off how fast your search engine is you
go ahead and conclude the search time
then of course in the results property
would be the actual array of all the
results that came back from the search
so best that on the next one now we're
switching gears here how do you
represent links inside the response sure
cell links links are queues inside of
your message that point so different
right so if we look at the netflix API
they're using something called web
linking there's actually a spec around
this an RFC you can see an HR up there
that's pointing to a URL where you can
find what we're looking for you see of a
rel value there in that link and they're
special meaning to that real value if
you look at netflix if documentation
will say that we don't person about
actor is an actor in a film and a title
associated associated with that Elijah
would visit the github API that we're
going for more of a Netflix API when
they were in beta but now there they've
changed it up a little bit under their
organization is easy or so if you look
at a repository of the 17 organization
you find the organization ser el you
would go to that URL to get to that
particular resource our recommendation
is to follow Netflix and the web looking
spec and a big part of that is because
there is a specification around that and
you can point your developers to that to
understand how to interact with your API
which is usually poor before it before
we cloth links and you might even set it
in went by pretty quickly how how do you
help people understand if they should
put links in their response or not it's
just you always do it you never do it
certain times you do it what's the
listed that he restricts for me to use
links yeah so I mean links are really
helpful for developers right so if
you're looking at a response message and
you see that there's a relationship
there between say a film and an actor
you can look at that message and
continue on your exploration of that API
right I find myself going back to the
documentation less and less and just
able to focus on I'll exploring that epi
so that's one huge benefit yeah and i
think the contrast is the alternative is
you what you hear the word templating
thrown around a lot like instead of
giving back the link you might just give
back the ID and a developer has to know
that this idea gets plugged into the
template in the right spot so in this
case coming back here's a catalog of
people so if i just saw the people i
being that i would grab that ID and say
hey i'm going to do a get on / people
and drop the ID and
at the end rest or that's sort of trade
off right correct and that takes some
context switching if you're doing
explore exploratory work and takes you
know some different coding structures
and then to make sure that you do the
ornate temples properly but yeah any
other kind of thing is correlated this
is all I need going out of band if you
don't include the link in the response
and the developers have to go a lot of
band you can go recent documentation or
something outside of the API to figure
out what to do next so right we all
other context switching as a big cost
and US bank right happens cool beans
okay so we'll move it how to represent
actions and as we do this Brian kept
saying like is there a better definition
for this or what what our actions right
and actions are typically state
transitions coming off of that
particular resource that you're looking
at so we can get some of the examples
here give up documents this so again we
see we're going away from the message
and we're looking at documentation to
figure out how to do this in this case
we're doing an update to a repository on
github when the documents you know the
HTTP method that you need to use your I
template you need to use and on the
input fields I couldn't find a good
example of this out in the wild in
public API is but if you look at the
four based API example it is taking
exactly what gift up is doing and
applying that in line formed based
meeting like HTML form so if you leave
with HTML you know reform tag there's a
method there's a URL in there where you
can you know where you go to dad execute
that method and their list of fields so
we're recommending the form based
approach seeing this more and more in
the wild not not too many folks but i
think it's it's something we need to
keep an eye on moving towards that form
based approach allows a lot of things
for instance hidden fields or a big
thing that we use in HTML forms today we
throw those into your API right that
means you have David coming back and
forth keeping that stateless nature to
your API and still getting what you need
on the server without affecting your
clients at all so to make this come to
life for me when this comes when that
when they actually comes back in my HTTP
response I would my code is going to go
ahead and parse this and then
whether I'm creating an HTML form or iOS
form and Android form I'm an introspect
this all the properties here and build
my form based off of that exactly and
then at the end of post or that started
the method that is telling me patch in
this case is going to go back to this
href so if I were building HTML form
that's obvious it's going to go there
and I'm doing iOS it's going to be an
API call with that data correct cool got
it how do we represent metadata so we
have a couple examples here flickr
include some metadata in line with their
items in this case it's a photo there's
not a whole lot of metadata there but
you know some exists Dropbox they
decided to have an entire metadata
resource to access so you know if you go
look at a file itself or a folder in
dropbox there's a lot of data associated
with that if it's the path if it's you
know how many bikes are there all sorts
of things so you know we like having
metadata in the response itself and
we'll move usually favor that but there
are cases to consider you know having
that meta resource and again that's when
your your metadata become so significant
that it actually should be modeled on
your API so I think this makes a lot of
sense for dropbox that it makes a lot of
sense for for flipping they should have
talked it all over but you know some
kind of meta hitting interesting but
it's good to have that in time so you
know as we're talking everything we've
been talking about for the vestry
ministers around designing the message
of response message the message design a
lot of what hypermedia thinking does is
address the message design so what can
we learn from other media types so Adam
Adam public one of the wheelie one of
the first media types out there to be
used for api's its attention was for
feeds and editing you know articles in
the list and things like that but one
important thing that they showed us is
to build a protocol around link
relations if you see if that link rel
equals at it should be in bold they're
there they're using that standard link
role
type to communicate to the developer or
the client that's consuming this this
API where to go to edit this particular
resource I wouldn't see this this too
much but XHTML this next lady dies
rights for urs that's not what's going
on here so the cool thing about XHTML is
that it's a valid XML which means that
partial errs like it quite a bit have a
difficult to build HTML parser because
they kind of allow quite a bit going on
in there whereas xml is pretty well
formed so this is from psycho our status
they're implementing an alp
specification that you can find out
there on the internet and helps has
certain meaning around classes such as
avatars users userlist search you can
see that in XHTML we're including that
in there and you really get that that
semantic connection so some people might
say it's a weird use of XHTML but you
know it exists it's out there and
there's a there's a gentleman on the API
craft who's really been pretty active
about pushing a system index HTML as a
standard right it's interesting stuff
cool okay now we have a few Jason based
hypermedia types this one's how how is
is really student towards augmenting
your existing API so if you have a Jason
message out there adding this underscore
links to your existing Jason message
which will hopefully not collide with
any with an existing underscore links
property you have and your j subject can
start adding some of those hypermedia
elements here we see the link relation
becomes like a key in this key value
pair inside the links object so we have
a link to self next and previous
iterating through orders in the
collection so sometimes there are
options for augmenting your existing API
without breaking clients
collection plus jason is a media type
out there that is trying to model adam
pub and what they were doing except in
Jason so it's you know a little more
palatable to to some folks it also
allows for extensions and in it you can
see that there are queries that are
modeled here but there's also write
templates that you can use so it sitting
back to those actions and allowing
actually editing the different resources
that you have so and then they're sorry
and siren has a mixture of all of these
so it's it's really taking a the goal
anyways to take a lot of the the best of
what we know about hypermedia and make a
media type that is suitable api's so
here we see actions just as we saw when
we were talking about using form-based
api's and entities which imply
relationship there they are also using
that lick relation that we talked about
being in the web linking spec and also
makes for navigational purposes of you
know next previous things like that cool
and who's the author of summer I guess I
should display that I am I the author
sorry click siren school soon all right
how do we accept binary data all right
you know this question comes up a lot
maybe I craft group because there's no
one way to do it because there's no one
way to do it right and is it seems that
folks only need to do this sometimes but
when they need to do it it's very
important that they give ton soon so one
method is to use multi-part form data
this is exactly what your browser does
when you're filling out a form and you
need to submit a file this is kind of
that looks like there's some
content-disposition that you put in
there too to name the field with a value
and you have the option of assigning
different content types to each bit they
sent so the second part there is is a
JPEG image that's being sent along with
that so you can do the same thing in
your API
another option is to just in line some
base64 encoded version of it so the
downside to that is when you base 64
encoded it gets a little bit bigger but
at least you can put it in a textual
representation right so you can have
your client do that base64 encoding and
then just dump this string in there and
submit it up to the server that will
decode it and then the last option is a
two-step process it's you know creating
a new resource to hold that metadata
that you have and then submitting a file
that attaches to it and I always say no
opt for multi-part form data first there
are a lot of tools out there that will
help you do this as a client and that's
pretty significant the big thing that
was no matter which one you choose and I
think multi-part for me is the way to go
just be consistent don't have three or
four different ways in your API to
upload a file it's just not worth the
headache caching caching is another one
of those topics that affect i'm really
not talking about everything do with
caching is what are the design
implications are not caching is that
right right cool so first we'll go
through different ways to do that right
so the three main ways to to do caching
one is exploration so you use a cache
control headers say this is private
which means that only the clients can
cash this no proxy in the middle should
be cashing this in a max age in seconds
so this is 30 days I think this is a
direct message to the client saying hold
on to this and it should be good for
this length of time right another method
is etags etags are sometimes calculated
is a checksum of a file or different
data elements that you have you can use
your some databases do a good like
revision number on each document that
they have or you can manage your own
keys for etags much like Twitter
they have like their own key generator
service but yeah so when you pull down a
resource representation will have any
tag associated with it and if you want
to make sure that you have the latest
you can do a gap at that same URL and
include the header if not match and
include any tag that you already that
you received if there are no tanks with
that then you get the latest response
third option is using the last modified
header as a hint how fresh the the
representation is if you get that's
modified back with your representation
the next time you go to get it you can
put a header in there that says if
modified since with that same date and
you only get it back if it's newer so
it's a network call but you don't get
the full body of the message back and
you know while there's no one particular
caching method to do at all times it
really depends on use cases a common
pitfall that we get into is that we
don't think about the client we think
about cashing in terms of saving
resources and saving bandwidth on the
server but we don't think about it on
the client right a lot of times that
client doesn't need to make another
network call and you know that saving
that time is very valuable for them so
just keep that away do we need a
JavaScript API so often folks ask we see
this in a number of ways where the API
and maybe the domain of the system
itself has some a lot of complexity
around it so maybe you do an API for say
payment processing and you can set
payments from credit cards checking
accounts paypal google wallet and so on
your api in order for a developer to
learn how to use the API and then
Express how to use it to through the
user interface to the end user it can be
very difficult so oftentimes there's
pressure on the API to maybe want to
start giving hints about UI elements or
how to actually use this and that's
always a mistake you want to clean
separation between the the API and the
consumer however some people think of
this as an SDK some people call it an
API the question is you're so there's so
much understanding of JavaScript I vsat
a rudimentary level that this kind of
presents itself as an anomalous thing
like should hey we build
kpi we have little bit of resources
should we use those guys to build the
next version of the API or should we do
with JavaScript API I'm feeling more and
more that if you're doing an API and you
want a really good adoption and you want
to have an easier job of explaining how
to use it to folks you should go ahead
and also create a JavaScript library or
JavaScript SDK or API however you want
to call it and if you want to see an
example of spokes who are doing this
really really well take a look at
LinkedIn the JavaScript API does a great
job of handling all of the
authentication stuff so the developers
don't have to get down on the weeds on
that and the the way that the JavaScript
library maps on sit the pants of the
core API is really transparent and it
fits really nicely so I do recommend if
this is a question you were thinking
about go ahead and tackle the JavaScript
API now should you do the iOS API an
Android API or SDK yeah maybe but that
you know take a look at your priorities
but definitely if you had to do one I
would do javascript and take a look at
LinkedIn cool what about posting data so
talk a little bit about actions and you
know submitting changes to state of our
representations this is more about let's
talk about how new serialize that data
how and what what form does it take when
we take that request and send it to the
server one options to use application
xww form URL encoded really long name
but is it's really simple it looks just
like a query string so some folks said
XML as the request body can get kind of
verbose sometimes as XML tends to do but
that's an option and then there's Jason
right so
we favor the for me well and coated
version it's it's pretty simple it's
easy there are certainly many different
tools out there that folks can use for
that is it wrong to use the alternatives
no but definitely favor the simplicity
all right how do we handle transactions
of the Caddy idea is we're not going to
do a deep dive on transactions we're
just going to gets at it and very likely
will do another web cast just on how to
handle transactions with an API right
let's take a look at it me safely he's
just so handsome in one way you could do
this you can model the transaction
directly in your API right for for this
example we're going to use the concept
of a shopping cart you can have in our
API we have some user they create a
shopping cart with post they get a 201
created back then you know from the
product catalog they add you know some
mittens to their their cart let me check
out right I mean it's it's just a matter
of creating that that transaction adding
items to it and then doing a commit
right certainly problems can happen you
can get errors back and you know you'll
have to deal with that yeah we'll talk
we'll talk more on that cool so in
summary we talked about the previous
editions for URI design we've got a new
book out there and there's a cheat sheet
at the top of the slide deck I can just
run you through really quickly what our
suggestions are for designing URIs and a
little bit on errors and revisions it's
kevin said start with api modeling it's
a good idea to create a common language
and a comment understanding among your
API team use OAuth the latest version
other for security it's almost always
the right one to use and keep in mind
when you're designing your response
messages that the message design is for
developers to parse into those resources
into some objects in their language and
it's a good idea to be terse and brief
and let them get to the data as soon as
possible while also including metadata
and notifications and things like that
we give you a quick a quick overview of
what's happening in the hypermedia area
with the different specs that are out
there
and as you dig into those you'll see
there's a lot to learn in terms of how
you should think about links and
designing your messages and finally we
talked touched briefly on transactions
and will do more about that later at
this what we'd like to go over to
questions and I know there are some
piling up in the Q&A area here but feel
free to start adding some more the first
this is from Burke Audrey thanks for
writing the question the question is
they making that they may get to this
but we have an exception in quotes which
is very verbal like we have a payment
engine that we want to expose and we
can't decide on the best way to model
that we don't need to store the results
no post or put and get seem strange any
thoughts so yeah we encountered this
pretty often if you are doing things in
your API and the words that express that
are things like calculate or exchange or
convert oftentimes those are on those
are non resource like API on its and we
suggest and you can read this in the
e-book we suggest to be very careful to
use verbs for those types of things and
documents and kind of demarcate that the
most part of this API as a bunch of
resources in it but there are
occasionally things you need to do which
are much more like algorithms and no
David artifacts created from it so treat
them separately and yeah I like the idea
of using verbs to do that just as you
out mine and that's a good general rule
for design right nothing is ever perfect
when you make it exception to the rule
make sure it's documented right cool
Michael Stewart asks how the links work
with the JSON response this is probably
asked at the point where we'd only shown
XML should we go back and show is that
Dana sirens going to example that yeah
right so there's there's a week at the
bottom there that is just a link to self
which is really common also the entities
can be seen like links here to where I'm
an owner resource that we're linking to
a dog so sorry includes all this in a
renter array all the the rel values are
in it right because we have more than
one some other formats don't do that but
example here is how how does the more of
a key value approach
can only have one rail value for the
resource cool thanks again Michael for
asking that question next one is from
Jason hunt maybe I missed this why would
you put this form based API on top of
rest doesn't rest already have a URL and
action yeah so that form based API is
just communicating which action you
should use to do that and which you are
I you should use to make that call and
again the alternatives put all that in
documentation but you lose a little bit
of evolvability on that right if your
your I start changing if maybe you want
to switch from a patch to a-put for
certain architectural reasons you'd have
to update documentation attention to
break your clients putting it right into
the message itself allows for that
evolution fantastic and really just
stresses this is you're talking about
doing one of the actions it's about that
you're not the current requests and
responses but we are you going to do for
the next request and response exactly
but I'm moving for cool alright the next
question is from lon Miller lon asks so
for the meta slide should each URL offer
a meta service foo / service / meta food
/ think / minute and so on so we hinted
at it how would you know that we should
think about having a dedicated meta
resource so how would you actually do it
so I don't think I'd have a meta service
but that doesn't feel right to me and
I'd make a meadow resource but only for
those resources that require it again we
really favor putting that in the message
encapsulated some kind of meta object
and inside the message one all possible
all right let's question from andreas
Tosh he asks XML vs. Jason isn't JSON
limited / less maintainable for example
you want to add attributes later or for
example if you want to add the currency
to a price later on see slides 1 1 0 2 2
1 12 of something on Google which we
won't click on it not because we can't
share the screen sure you know this is
almost like the which is your favorite
text editor battle there are pros and
cons all over the place with Jason with
some of these hypermedia formats I've
shown they are extensible if you look at
the speck you can add
I think there's a new link relation type
called profile I don't know if it is a
full-blown standard yet it might be an
internet draft but the profile link
relation will be a way to mix in certain
functionality into an existing JSON API
right now it work with XML time cool my
taking that is XML definitely has a much
stronger set of tooling and wisdom and
knowledge that's out there in the world
especially in the fortune 500 co 2000
enterprises JSON is the is the
representation for javascript in
javascript is like the second everybody
second language in the world of
programming it's not the first language
so those are I think you we can we
suggest supporting both make JSON your
default but definitely there are cases
where XML is gonna make more sense lon
dollar SYE tags is the e-tag value of
crc or a transaction receipt number of
both easy tag only useful for a
deterministic service you know the e-tag
can be calculated anyone you want
there's no general rule in HTTP spec
about how you calculate a new tag so
again I mean use whatever makes sense
cool Jason Kemp asks how our patch
requests handled on the back end are you
parsing it into a dynamic sequel string
or what are the best practices around
that we're currently using an ORM and to
DMV framework if that's not net well I
mean there are a bunch of pieces to this
question here first of all if you're
putting your you putting your API
directly over your data layer there's
sherman there's a lot you have to think
about their would you generate a dynamic
sequel string I don't know that doesn't
feel too comfortable for me I probably
modeling some kind of API model between
between that debt service and the
back-end data stuff good cool Mike Rossi
asks what is your opinion of odata Kevin
what's your opinion of whole data with
my opinion about it you know I think the
OData guys are headed
the direction with where they're going
they're the latest version at least last
I heard I'm not entirely close to it I
think they've had and they were based on
Adam pub at some point maybe they have
other formats that they're doing now
again this is kind of how do we model
sequel over our API right they really
get into how you filter results never
comes like that you know what there are
cases that I am comfortable with that
good usually I'm not okay what's up cool
question from the vector V in case we
would like to call it the eyes from
static pages for example HTML and not
from PHP or other programs i imagine the
key thing is that the build other
program front of the server is there any
way to embed the credentials on your
respective of OAuth basic etcetera and
that make them fall prey to other eyes
we deal with this all the time as we're
building apps yeah so just with static
pages how do you protect that you don't
you don't yeah and that's where using we
of course apogee we have a product a
free product available on FG com that
will allow you to create a proxy and you
can store some that information in the
proxy keep it off of the dynamic pages
and do some do some stuff back that way
but it's pretty tough overall yeah okay
next question is from bish how can a
client requests templates for creating
new resources and I think that's what
you talked about the action right
actually see that in siren and in the
collection plus Jason they have right
templates easy enough yeah so user use
dancers use a media type that supports
it alright um anis fuck swallow asks how
to facilitate the XML transformation of
JSON response there are a bunch of tools
that can help you do that there's open
source packages at the G has some stuff
other folks have some stuff to transform
XML into JSON sometimes it's really
straightforward in fact the XML the JSON
is actually often simpler than the other
way around but
which was out there don't easier to find
out google you can start with a pudgy if
you want okay Christopher asks to
provide minimal security / tracking is
an access token enough I have a bunch of
JavaScript widgets which clients will
embed into their user interfaces and i'm
planning on proving each client
providing i guess each client with the
token the data is not private a lot
seems like overkill oooff might be an
overkill if you're not using user data
right if your service manages user data
and you have clients that need to access
that user data Olaf is perfect otherwise
you know one of the other methods might
better suit your needs and that's fire
that could be ssl-certificates even if
client us is all certificates and basic
off pencil you need right uh David
Campbell asks or I guess it's kind of
influenced can we buy the better word
for notifications and response I think
we absolutely could that has way too
many syllables in it but that's that's
the one that we liked it seemed to have
the most relevance for what was going on
the real the real point for putting
notifications in there as our suggestion
was just to say you can have a section
for medic made us metadata about the
response you should have the response
itself but then keep in mind that there
are things that are a better happening
around the app more broadly or more
globally that could be interesting to
store as a separate thing to do so for
your app it might be notifications for
someone else's app it might be alerts or
info or warnings whatever it is that
it's just sorta like the idea the model
the pattern that we like to be idiot
piggybacking more generic stuff on top
of each response because the app could
just render it when it gets new data
back great great point though thanks for
that question alright next one Matthew
reinbold what are some rules of thumb an
authorization versus authentication
meaning making sure the client has
permission to make requests versus the
user having permissions to modify their
data Oh auth to for both yeah so off
tune for both so it ought to whether or
not the client has permission is
something that you're going to have to
manage
your client registration process and
your client policies and since expose
about versus a user okay authorization
authentication don't get it was that
avatar and how many times have you
really owe us back in the past month god
I think I'm up to seven now one document
all right our last question for today
from Peter how many items would you
limit a JSON response to in the case
that each object has 10,000 cute I'm
sorry that HIV has 10 key value pairs I
use something like sending 300 merchants
location to the client on one response
to too big / network heavy in the
previous version of this we talked about
just a rule of thumb around 10 we have
you know we have 10 fingers we have a
mostly decimal based calming system all
over the world so I think using a using
10 as your default makes sense if your
data is really really big make it
smaller than 10 de this really really
small make it bigger than 10 but I think
started with 10 is a good rule of thumb
and test this out to right I mean have
clients out there that you're testing
with and if you know you're gonna have a
bunch of mobile clients see how this
feels on a mobile client if you know
you're going to have a bunch of you know
back-end systems that our clients test
it from there because that could change
your payload folks thanks a bunch for
tuning in today we appreciate your
questions and your engagement as we
mentioned before of this webcast and all
our webcasts are available on YouTube at
youtube.com slash Apogee please join us
on the google group called api craft if
you just do a search for api crafts will
find us fantastic community folks all
moving the craft ivp eyes forward and
feel free to contact us directly those
are our emails and our twitter accounts
and of course there's the apogee twitter
account as well thanks for tuning in and
we'll catch you next time thanks
everybody bye