you
I don't know if the conference will have
slides up somewhere in any case you can
get it from my side PDF I always like to
start explaining the range of levels not
a classification into beginner
intermediate advanced which makes
absolutely no sense because of course
every talk covers a range in also like
to call the levels by the names given to
them in the no theater and later in
Aikido and other martial art there's a
phase where you're learning shoe there's
a phase where you're detaching from the
learning into the real word ha and
there's a phase where you transcend
learning read this talk addresses
anything anybody bought to the rankest
beginner definitely all intermediate
layers if you're really advanced if you
spent a lot of your time and energy
thinking about abstraction you may well
get a bit bored in which case I will not
be offended if you leave so obstruction
is a somewhat abstract theme so let's
make it a bit more concrete we work
think and operate on a tower of
abstraction I developed this to address
friends we're saying I don't do
abstraction I program in assembly
language you can't get any less abstract
than that well any more abstract but you
know assembly language is an abstraction
of machine code which i'm coding there
in extra decimal which is an obstruction
of signals controlling complex
integrated circuits which abstract
components built out of gates which
where a gate is the abstraction of
certain arrangement of transistors they
transistor is an abstraction of a
certain layout of dopants on a media the
reasoning in this term is obstructing
over the actual particles moons and
variants and photons that are doing the
work the particles are an abstraction of
a grid which is an abstraction of
Schrodinger's equation and I'm sure
somebody who's done more serious physics
than I could explain to me what is
Schrodinger's abstracting on so why
don't we program directly by tweaking
Schrodinger's equation why bother with
all these levels of abstraction all the
way to assembly language and I'm told
there are even higher levels more
distance from from their model of
reality well essentially we're looking
for leverage leverage is a term that
comes from a physical lever which lets
me move a huge boulder I couldn't
possibly move without a lever to amplify
my force leveraged by metaphor is used
for example when you borrow money to
invest more than you currently have in
your pocket great idea it does imply
things however if it goes wrong has
happened you may recall in 2008 for the
leverage in the monetary sense it can
amplify the crash at least as much so
that's why the stock is balancing
between singing the praise of
abstraction as leverage warning about
the dangers of abstraction as leverage
and trying to give some guidelines on
how to do abstractions right to maximize
their positives and keep their negatives
under control you really cannot live
without abstraction that actually
applies to all of human life and thought
but especially applies to what we're all
doing knowledge work not necessarily
programming some of us may use may well
use programming as a mere tool to do a
DNA synthesis or financial wizardry or
whatever but the point is that if you're
doing knowledge work you're using or
consuming not consuming as in once
you're done there
no more they're they're still there so
using abstraction layers and often a lot
of what you are producing on the way to
whatever your final goal is is other
abstraction layers on top therefore it
becomes a very attractive-looking I
could use the slice of that layer cake
so we can't live without it but can we
live with it joel's polski now that's
known as they core developer of stack
overflow but even before then it was a
well-known blogger and software
entrepreneur and so on expressed once
what he called spoke is low which is all
abstractions leak what does that mean
we'll explore that in more detail it
doesn't necessarily mean a dike with a
whole Linda poor kid trying to stem it
it actually means all obstructions are
subject to boggs excessive load
deliberate attacks to ward against these
when you use an abstraction you must
understand the levels below the
abstraction or you're completely
completely defenseless against the leak
and this was the whole point of spoke is
low i'm sure you can find you can find
his essay in a line is a great writer
but what i'm adding to this is
obstruction should leak not only do they
they should in control designed
architected ways we'll see what i mean
by this then there's an important aside
abstraction can slow you down everybody
will probably be nothing saying yeah if
I program to abstractly my program will
be slow it's not so much that it's about
your mind remember your technology
changes all the time your mind not so
much as I keep saying we are on release
1.0 beta of human beings and there
doesn't seem to be an
to prospect for an upgrade in sight so
whatever deals with the functioning of
your mind is probably something you're
going to have to work with for quite a
while so in Psychological Science in
2008 McCrea Lieberman trope in Sherman
published constructional level and
procrastination essentially it's a
well-known fact that remote events are
construed mentally at higher levels of
abstraction so if you think what did I
have for lunch today you can probably
have it in your mind at a rather
concrete level I had some lettuce and I
skipped the zucchini but I had the fish
um pretty concrete if you're thinking
what did I have for lunch a year ago
exactly you while I probably did have
lunch likely some vegetable and some
protein you are inevitably abstracting
the nature of your lunch which is remote
in time in this case the reverse also
holds which is the point the scholars
established and published in in
Psychological Science the higher the
abstraction your construing something
they more likely it is to that you will
procrastinate that result is well
established for undergrad students of
psychology that remember whenever you
get empirical results about from from
psychological journals and so on which
are well worth reading you know they
will be accurate for undergrad students
of that discipline because those are the
only experimental subjects the poor guys
can get without having to like shell out
big money so that that's sometimes that
actually matters so there's the famous
case of the attachment you know they we
it's well established
tend to value what we have more than
what we lack if that was universally
true there would be no such thing as
trait because each protagonist would
value what they already have more than
what they could get by in exchange well
apparently that only applies to
undergrad students and actual traders in
the market are completely free of that
mental effect so keep that in mind let
me very briefly give some example if
they if a task is described as a write
500 words essay about today's lecture
students tend to actually do it pretty
promptly if it's about write an essay on
a lecture you found very interesting I
mean it shouldn't take forever to think
ok I've had no 20 lessons so far which
one was very interesting but it's just
one obstruction level away from today's
lecture which they just heard too so
it's very present very concrete to them
a lot more will fail to deliver that
essay or deliver it late that's an
established right so abstraction leads
to procrastination is that bad well as
usual we consult to the holy text is a
Zen of Python take your open your laptop
say open a Python say import this and
meditate on it again now is better than
never although never is often better
than right now like 0 zen Oracles and so
on it kind of mysterious what do these
things be ok here's the context the
first part refers to what I was talking
about this morning good enough is good
enough don't wait until some new feature
or whatever is perfect release it now
how people use it listen to
other feedback iterate improve iterate
improve the second part refers the
situation where you're forced to keep
backwards compatibility if you add a bad
feature if it's a design error to have
the feature at all you will be way down
for years even even when you make a
release whose whole purpose is breaking
backwards compatibility like Python 3
was respect to python to you can decide
also finally get to abolish the worst
feature I ever had the idea of
introducing into Python lambda Guido was
old decided to to abolish lambda in
vital 3 he got such a surge of hate mail
from Python users that for the first
time I've ever heard of in the long time
of knowning well he stepped back and put
lambda back in you do one of those
errors once your holes forever I mean I
don't think python is a bad language
because in Atlanta it would be a better
one if it didn't have it but so
sometimes you want to procrastinate to
the point of never doing something
that's not a bad idea sometimes most of
the time you don't so to achieve think
concrete consider for example the
getting things done they that's a title
of the original book by now there are a
bazillion books self improvement courses
and so on the it has many principles to
really help you manage your time but the
most important is always have front and
center you're single next action but
there may be a million things you will
need to do to accomplish your life
changing universe changing ways but one
at a time what's the next one next
single action also in interaction design
user centric design you don't write
anymore like in the battle days user
story saying
the user wants to do this and that the
user needs to access this information
you design personas specific almost
caricature all users your software will
have like if it's a trading software
there will be John the nuba trader with
fast video game experience so you can
already start imagining he wants fast
action a lot of graphics information
overload and the other hand there's mark
the season trader from Hammurabi's time
is still grumbling that he can't use the
cuneiform characters on clay tablets so
you will be designing for John and for
market for a collection of personas
these this artificial concreteness if
you will will guide you to do your
design best or adjacent read of
37signals put it you find I often quote
37signals because they're kind of super
design guys which is a skill I
absolutely lack so I kind of revere them
from afar prefer action to abstraction
that if you have to choose be concrete
so you can do something they what you
probably thought when a set of structure
you can slow you down is the so called
abstraction penalty steppin off so the
architect of the C++ standard template
library published a very learned paper
showing that C++ allows you to program
at lower struction higher abstraction
and there's a penalty as in extra run
time spent if you program at the higher
level of abstraction however this is not
a fundamental rule it's at issue a
detail of quality of implementation I
said I believe in the latest C++
compilers it doesn't really hold anymore
that's taken decades but they're
implementing things right in fact in
Python we should be usually thinking of
an abstraction abstraction bonus
consider for example what I personally
consider Raymond hangers I don't think
is around anymore but he gave us a
wonderful keynote yesterday
i trow tools if say you just want to do
nothing 42 times they doing nothing is a
bit of strange thing but instead of the
past you can have something else but
what's the overhead of your looping well
you can try range you can try x range in
python 27 happens to be a bit faster by
the way all these are measured on this
old macbook air if you have a faster
machine everything will be faster in
proportion the fastest way by a little
is actually to use i trow tools repeat
it doesn't tell you it doesn't give you
increasing number it just gives you non
42 times but it does that does that a
little faster than even xrange there's
issues of abstractions in python where
the advantage is even bigger like orders
of magnitude this is for example I've
got a string and I want the reverse
strength exactly so they detailed
concrete way to do it is to do reversed
which gives you a generic sequence join
it up with empty string and that works
and it and for the string being
abracadabra it takes 113 microsecond on
this machine but if you do it at a
higher level of abstraction by indexing
it's rising to be technical with what my
wonderful wife Anna once dubbed the
Martian smiley that is square bracket
colon colon minus 1 so from to stride
from nothing thus beginning to nothing
thus the end stride minus 1 so go in
reverse that takes six times less the
higher abstraction level gains you a
huge speed up well huge it's a micro
second and something but on the other
hand
that's what the thing is taking so don't
be summarizing this part don't be
worried about Python beings lower if you
read if you program abstractly that's
probably not be the case just wonder
about not procrastinating for being too
abstract yourself remember Python 27 and
even better Python 35 haven't tried 36
yet it's an alpha are evolving
technology they keep getting better
you're not you you want to get better a
bit but you do have brain that works
that it was evolved over a million years
in of ancestors roaming the savanna
hunting and gathering and that's not
easily worked off so let's come to the
old abstractions leak that's how all
obstruction leak is spall skis law I'm
trying to explain okay why why can't I
make perfect run well all obstruction
leak because all obstructions lie
inevitably as one of the great engineers
of the 20th century Korzybski said the
map is not the territory horrigan luis
borges one of the great writers of the
century actually made a beautiful short
story explaining why because if the map
where the territory it would completely
cover the whole state letting no
sunlight go down to the crops and they
the harvest would fail and everybody
would be starving the map isn't and
cannot be the territory it has to
abstract a lot so therefore it lies in
some respect and therefore inevitably it
will leak it will not correspond
perfectly to what is trying to map if it
did it would be completely useless would
be just a
copy of the underlying level level of
abstraction so before you can abstract
you best understand every detail I use
the verb grok founded by one of my
favorite writers and Anna's Robert
Heinlein it means to drink really deep
to enjoy and get every drop of your
drink before you can step back in the
sense abstraction is stepping back you
must be close and this is actually a
quote from a rather more unusual source
the book of five rings even if you're
got zero interest in Aikido or any other
form of fencing the book of five rings
cell has a lot to teach you and this is
what before you can is talking about
well at one level it is talking about an
Aikido duel and they crucial move of
stepping back before you can do that you
must be close to your adversary so you
must have been close before you can
afford to step back but it is also
that's why I recommend the book as
general reading it there's also always a
more abstract metaphorical level before
you can abstract from something you must
have been close to that you can only
abstract when you know all details you
can never know all details that doesn't
mean therefore never abstract which
would be in a digital logic in this more
eastnor form it therefore always keep a
very humble attitude you are doing
something that's not in your powers but
you must do it anyway so be very humble
be very flexible listen to feedback and
be ready to correct your course let me
take my very favorite obstruction if in
the technical field if I only have to
choose one the
CIP family of networking protocols it's
really a great abstraction how they
layers correspond to the data or or
payload and and get enriched with
headers and footers in some cases as
they navigate through lower more
concrete layers so if all obstructions
sleek as I claim or or giorgos chose
polka dot what does TCP week well to be
sufficiently generic it leaks trust it
was designed in the era of brave-hearted
spotless nights and evil overlords and
nobody had any trouble distinguishing
them the whole stack leak so all over
the place from below arp caches are
subject to poisoning from above dns
caches are subjected to poisoning from
the side bgp can be vendacious from
inside anything is possible the
traditional application protocols like
FTP and telnet sent password in clear
where anybody happening to listen could
get your passwords and it goes on
forever this is actually a rather data
that couldn't find an updated one but
this is what network managers are
worried about the green on the right is
bought-in botnets so essentially the
distributed denial-of-service attacks
everything else is actually TCP leaks
leaks of trust everything from BGP
hijacking including accidents and so and
so forth don't know how familiar you are
with network but a PDF dress solution
protocol is our look local network
managers messages every everybody's
keeping
map of Internet Protocol addresses to
the lot of the Machine address m.a.c and
there is no authentication or validation
of that is not really feasible the way
it was designed from the first place as
they mentioned this morning one thing
you have to have from the start because
retrofitting it drives you crazy is
security so ARP to this day hardly as
any insecurity so if either they evil
evil for evil has a faster machine it
can respond to all requests for AARP
identification saying me me that IP is
my mac and that blocks alice's slower
machine from actually giving the real
map so anything on the local network
that's meant for alice goes to eve
instead from the outside you can do the
same for dns since you're not originally
communicating to an internet protocol
address but to a dns name you risk
somebody interjecting i am the
authoritative server for this domain and
the proper IP years which is is own
rather than the one it should be this is
an actual diagram of border gateway
protocol attack court-mandated attack in
2012 Pakistani court decided that this
YouTube thing was an insult to Islamic
value and ordered ISPs in Pakistan to
block YouTube which is of course was at
the time transmitting from California so
how they do that they came up with an
idea well let's steal their network
ranges by hijacking they border gateway
protocol locally unfortunately then
local hijacks that was sending all
youtube traffic to a local black hole
leaked accidentally presumably to I
think Hong Kong and from them through
all the world and for about two hours
all traffic to and from YouTube was
actually going to a black hole in
somewhere in Pakistan that's so bgp is
fortunately obscure enough I mean let's
be serious who of you could program a
BGP server great we have one expert so
you see it has been and is continuously
being improved is much harder at the
lower levels like AARP so we will never
be without leaks even in a wonderful
stack of abstraction however leaks may
be good especially when they're
carefully designed for a purpose suppose
I want to make a remote distributed file
system an early attempt and we're
talking decades ago well I'll just have
to emulate the local one no reason to do
anything different the problem is the
less local your file system actually was
the costlier was the abstraction from
everything from semantics to locking to
reliability I don't know how many of you
are fought with trying to make record
locking work on NFS let's say it's not
fun the point is that file system is a
splendid abstraction local file system
is not it's a concrete thing and don't
subclass concrete classes is a great
principle of opportunity into
programming but as you see we're talking
about a higher level of abstraction it
applies there to the older is our
principal engineer at Google is
unfortunately taken down his blog but
thanks to the internet archive you can
just browse for don't subclass concrete
classes har and you'll see it is talking
about Java but really half of what is
saying applies perfectly well to Python
or
even to architecting a file system the
fact that emulating a local file system
with the distributed one is a horrible
idea doesn't mean the obstruction is a
bad thing you should disrupt the right
thing that is have a file system
abstraction and deliberately leaked for
example with methods asking or telling
the file system something up local
distributed file system will work like
set a time out you your local file
system presumably doesn't have a way to
set it arm out because hey it's a local
disk spindle on my own machine how take
a millisecond and 10 micro second why
would I need to time out well because
maybe it's not if it's a distributed one
it could be somewhere in Australia and
the connections are slightly slower so
you need systematic and usable leaks and
of course in the local file system their
implementation will be trivial so it
will accept a timeout parameter and for
example it could ignore it no problem so
I would really like to teach you how to
obstruct right but it's a bit too hard
I'm not quite sure I have fully
understood so I'm definitely going to
teach you are a much more expert how do
we abstract wrong well first of all you
want to make an abstract interface well
you have one class that works just fine
let me make that interface by
essentially abstracting everything that
cost us I guarantee you this will
surface some implementation detail that
are not conceptually part of the
abstraction subclassing concrete classes
as how are warned against is also pretty
much that the concrete class is never
going to be the right base for
subclassing because it's always has
implementation details by by being
concrete make the obstruction of the
multiple classes that need to implement
the same interface at
a major scale you can have encapsulation
error for example in the microsoft NFC
library all throughout release for each
windows had a private member which was a
toolbar class that window would use
which meant if you wanted to use to
customize a toolbar you were completely
out of luck because you essentially had
to copy the whole window class and to
edit the thing going to get larger scale
as anybody ever heard of taligent
taligent was a joint venture between
Apple IBM and I believe you have
occurred in the early stages to make the
world a better place by doing a lot of
frameworks a lot of those frameworks
were based on all those experience with
one application in that field you can
guess how well that went down in how
long taligent lasted ok I will actually
try to mention how to abstract well you
have to master at least one or two
layers below the one you're designing
the abstraction at to understand how is
in several ways that abstraction could
be implemented if there's only one way
the abstraction can possibly be
implemented it's not a real abstraction
it masquerades as one it's really as
concrete as the only possible
implementation so better be deeply
familiar with several possible
implementation it's best if you also
think from the other side several
intended uses how are different systems
going to use this interface this
abstraction you can't afford any
blinders or shortcuts saying go I don't
need to care about the users I'm
focusing my instruction I don't need to
care about the implementation I'm
focusing on my distraction you do need
to care both on the above n below
remember you can be the next
user of that interface you can be that's
possibly even more likely the next
implementer of that interface once
you've implemented and published your
neural interface well you need to put
code where your mouth is and actually
implemented the Golden Rule doing to
somebody not doing to somebody else what
you wouldn't want to be done to yourself
is actually a core principle of software
development when you design an
abstraction think of yourself as the
next user and next implementer and I
strongly recommend the old wiki at sea
to point calm for a deeper discussion of
this very thing of issues but that
sounds like a really really hard job I
me now I should be looking at
implementation end users that's like
well you if according to Donald news you
can that's an interview we gave to the
dr. Dobbs journal the psychological
profiling oh we actually use the term
computer scientist but I don't I don't
like to insult people by using the term
let's say a good software developer is
mostly the ability to shift level of
abstraction low level to high level see
something in the small see something in
the large and a great software developer
sees things simultaneously at the low
level and the high level of distraction
in other word the microcosm is the
macrocosm to get all cosmic on you
there's a wonderful books on the subject
but they tend to be in the exoteric a
section of the library of the bookstore
rather than the technical one but it
still applies to the design of
abstraction and just to quote not for
the first time jacent read you really
have to do this homework he's talking
about copying explaining in that dot URL
the problem is copying is that copying
skips understand understanding is the
way you
roll you have to understand why
something works why something is how it
is if you just copy it you don't you
miss the understanding you're just
repurposing the last layer not
understanding layers underneath in other
words it's not ever going to be any good
he's talking about copying but you know
what use existing level high level
abstractions blindly even though it
probably violates no copyright law or
nothing but still if you don't
understand why is it this way how does
this help the implementer or the user or
both then you're not understanding
you're not growing you're not getting a
real education so Jeff Atwood the
partner of Joe's polski in the
foundation of staccato saw put it don't
rain then the wheel unless you plant
learning more about wheels in which case
it may be a painful experience when you
have your first attempt but by the time
you've made it round again you
understand why the distance between the
point touching of a ground and the hell
is constant one good example of hacks of
deliberately inserted in an architecture
is in Google App Engine specifically the
Python version they're often
unfortunately not quite as familiar with
many other languages supported
essentially everything that's happening
in App Engine goes through a layer of
remote procedure calls to the servers to
Google servers which supply the various
services data store
user identification everything that need
funnel architecture has already been
used ever since the very first days of
App Engine to offer a local development
server which essentially runs exactly
all the open-source part that's above
the RPC but simulates the RPC locally so
it serves it locally so you can do your
development without bothering to upload
code to Google all the time so let's
focus on that RPC how do you for example
do testing everything is going through
specifically they make sync call
function in epic proxy stuff map they
traditional and wrong technique is to
monkey patch it so you get the actual
call you write your own fake which for
example does more logging or or measure
times or let you control interactively
and after doing all that goes back to
the original and you put you monkey
patch the fake India you will note that
the monkey is actually very sad you may
wonder why isn't this neat no it isn't
take for example the memcache client
object the memcache client object has
they make sinkhole at as the default
value of mixing call this is like all
all default values are computed once at
Def time so the moment then the memcache
client object is imported the module
containing this is imported the make
sinkhole is fixed to the real one and
all your monkey patching after the fact
will never change it this is
the crucial bit and it's very normal
when guido van rossum for a few years
joined Google to work on App Engine he
came up with a better idea hugs
deliberately have a pre hook and a
phosphor actually for every you can have
the pre call and the post call hooks to
every every function there and that's a
systematic leak around the API calls
what if you don't have a natural funnel
such as an RPC look at your application
look at your architecture you'll find
some there are going to be key
semantical bottlenecks for example if
you query a database consider adding
systematically a pre hook a change of
pre hooks which accept the sequel and
may modified or post end post hooks
which accept the results and can modify
them if you have a synchronous
architecture events and callbacks are
great semantic stopping points it's the
pre and post hooks approximate the
design pattern observer template method
is a bit rigid but you can use it look
at they to the Python to Python 3 has
changed things a bit implementation of
the cue class but the one I have time to
cover is designed for this purpose it's
a design pattern dependency injection
for example say you have you want to
make a scheduler so you add event by
pushing something on a priority queue
and when you run you get the thing wait
until its appointed time and then make
it happen the priority queue by the way
is an obvious construct on top of the
heap cube module I don't know why it was
never added it should
obviously have been so that's the
Knights of structure however you have a
problem how do you test this without
long delays well the problem is or how
do you integrate it with other event
groups they think concretely depends on
the time sleep and phone calls so you
could hatch it with monkey patching
which is a subtle hidden communication
in via dark alleys or you could use
dependency injection do you recognize
this from the point before where I
explain why not to monkey patch just use
time time and time sleep at the default
values and then save them up just like
sked in Python 2 standard library does
and dependency injection is a great way
to hook this is for example a fake time
which justice for testing asleep just
advances the fake time indicator and
this is where we see the exact same code
again but this time we understand why
this is not so you can do dependency
injection into the API call if the hooks
aren't enough you can use dependency
injection and this takes us to you na
again this is i don't know why i forgot
the HTTP this case but it's over there
incidentally this URL is where you can
get the early release of the 3rd edition
of python in a nutshell which i'm
writing together with my wife anna and
steve holden the inventor of pike on and
what you get there is ebooks because of
why about once a month you can you can
get updates all the way until the final
release which may be at the beginning of
next year you get all formats of of
ebooks from PDF to
Moby's to epubs they're all drm free and
guaranteed to stay free of DRM forever
and if at checkout you apply the
discount code oath d which stands for
author discount you'll get a fifty
percent off on and the big deal is that
if you do that you get to send us
feedback in time for us to react as
deeply as appropriate if you wait to buy
the paper edition and point out some
problem there we may do some minor fixes
if I fix a type or something in arata
but that's about it because of the whole
structure of the book is by then set in
paper which isn't quite as bad as being
set in stone but pretty much if you send
us feedback now and you convince sense
that we should change something deeply
we have months of time to do so so
please get or pirate I haven't said that
copies of this and send me feedback
thank you so much
so we have some time for questions thank
you um anyone who is designing
abstractions I think should hear your
talk or see your slides and that would
be great I'm using some libraries that
other people who've written who haven't
seen your slides yet and so sometimes
I'm faced with a choice between monkey
patching subclassing a concrete class or
you know copying or doing something else
awful I don't know that's if those are
open source libraries remember the
nuclear option fork if they're not open
source libraries I'm sorry for you but
there's nothing I can do to help other
questions so thank you very much for
your talk um I have a question about
dependency injection I generally don't
like to use dependency injection because
i feel like it ends up polluting all the
signatures of all my functions and the
classes definitions and so on is there
some way around it that's clean and
elegant in python they would recommend
so consider how does this pollute the
signature compared with one where you
were not able to customize this a
dependency injection must always come
with by definition is part of the
pattern with a default poly you just
don't need to use dependency injection
in a certain case you don't which is
probably not the normal case is in
operation in production you just don't
pass it but this is there for your tests
and occasional we're needs where you
need to hook up in for example a
scheduler to I don't know QT event loop
or something which isn't something you
do every day the signature could
perfectly well and with the self
and in that case you would not be able
to do dependency injection when you need
it but you can still call it without any
arguments and all behind
I just wanted to add to that the
generally dependency injection can be
replaced with registry if you look at
the Martin Fowler site his Java guy java
promote the dependency injection with
spring he also lists a registry as
another way of doing the same thing in
Python community if you look at the old
soap packages you will find that you can
use interface register utility that
provides that interface and then provide
your own and register instead of that
one to go together the familiar
registries tend to be global objects
when I can avoid Global's I avoid
Global's hi I was wondering what do you
do when you don't have the ability to
pass on your dependency dependency
injected object for instance you're
calling some other library which might
have like you referred to before might
have cashed the original time that time
and time not sleep here so essentially
if I'm calling an intermediate library
which doesn't support dependency
injection and the dependency injection
is needed on the lower levels that's
when I if the lower levels are
supporting dependency injection and an
intermediate layer of abstraction is
suppressing that will go back to the
advice to a previous questioner offer a
pull request to improve the intermediate
library if they don't accept it consider
forking it well I think we're three
minutes past the scheduled I think we
have two minutes
okay hi just curious how do you feel
about syntactic macros like macro pi as
an abstraction and an alternative for
dependency injection I've I used macros
back in the days when I programmed him
scheme I thought they were the cat's
pajamas until I started debugging macro
using buggy code by now I've been one of
those who fought really really hard
against a ver having macros in Python I
I like what you see is what you get and
the point of magro macros is making sure
that what you see is not what you get so
not particularly friendly I realize they
sound like an awesome idea until you
start trying to debug with them another
concept i got fell out of love with very
deeply is code generation hey why do i
have to code all this sequel I can just
strike right or use an object-relational
mapping sure now try having a bog and
debugging machine-generated sequel kodwa
haha sorry i'll write seagull I think
that's all the time we have thank you
all very much for your attention and see
you at the next talk
you